<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://psfedo3.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://psfedo3.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-10-15T12:48:46+00:00</updated><id>https://psfedo3.github.io/atom.xml</id><title type="html">Psfedo3</title><subtitle>RCCG Pastor seeds family of Edo province 3</subtitle><entry><title type="html">About the Pastor Seed Family</title><link href="https://psfedo3.github.io/articles/About-The-Pastors-Seed-Family.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="About the Pastor Seed Family" /><published>2020-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://psfedo3.github.io/articles/About-The-Pastors-Seed-Family</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://psfedo3.github.io/articles/About-The-Pastors-Seed-Family.html">&lt;p&gt;
The Pastors' Seeds Family of The Redeemed Christian Church of God is the fellowship of the seeds(children) of Pastors and Ministers in the Redeemed Christian Church of God. This does not limit our reach as we welcome the association with other Bible-believing ministries.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The Pastors Seed Family (PSF) of the Redeemed Christian Church of God is a body of Pastors, Ministers and Workers children (seeds) between the ages of 13 – 30 years. They are driven by the vision of living a godly lifestyle for other youths and young adults to emulate.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
PSFites has been involved in several CSR activities across the nation. For over 3 years now, this has been an annual commitment.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;gotham&quot;&gt;Vision Statement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To raise and build a generation of children of Levites whose goal is to:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;h2 gotham&quot;&gt;Make Heaven&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;articles-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Take as many people along with us.
Help youths and parents fulfill destiny and ministry and become a dominant positive influence in RCCG and the world at large
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Be a model for youths in RCCG and all over the world to follow.
Bridge the gap between the younger and older generation particularly between the youths/pastors seeds and the pastors thus stopping the max exodus of youths from the RCCG.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;gotham h2&quot;&gt;Mission&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;article-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Holiness will be our lifestyle
We will organize impacting and life changing events and programmes in RCCG parishes, areas, zones, provinces and regions across the world.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;article-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Our programmes shall be interactive, captivating, motivating,inspiring, educative, informative, and interesting and life changing and shall cover but not be limited to the following core areas:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holiness &amp;amp;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Career,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relationship,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Etiquette,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fashion &amp;amp; Dress Sense,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Annointing &amp;amp; Deliverance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bible &amp;amp; Church Doctrine,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entrepreneurship &amp;amp; Financial Empowerment,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nation Building,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Academics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leadership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spiritual Training and Warfare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health and Psychological Wellbeing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sexual Purity,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spiritual Growth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We shall encourage our members to enroll in the Believer’s Baptismal Class, Workers – in – Training and RCCG doctrinal teachings. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We shall liaise and partner with the Christ the Redeemer’s Ministries through her daughter organizations such as the Christ the Redeemer’s School Movement, School of Disciples, Redeemed Christian Fellowships, Redeemed Christian Corpers’ Fellowships, etc &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We shall liaise with the Education and Training arm of the RCCG through the CPLMT –Christian, RCBC - Redeemed Christian Bible College, RECSOM – Redeemed College and School of Missions. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We shall liaise with pastors – in – charge of parishes, areas, zones, provinces, regions, countries to ensure our programs have widespread coverage. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We shall engage professionals, seasoned and anointed teachers and preachers of the Word and performance coaches to impact, counsel, motivate and challenge members. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networking will be one of the main feature of our activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Psfedo3</name></author><category term="About" /><summary type="html">The Pastors' Seeds Family of The Redeemed Christian Church of God is the fellowship of the seeds(children) of Pastors and Ministers in the Redeemed Christian Church of God. This does not limit our reach as we welcome the association with other Bible-believing ministries. The Pastors Seed Family (PSF) of the Redeemed Christian Church of God is a body of Pastors, Ministers and Workers children (seeds) between the ages of 13 – 30 years. They are driven by the vision of living a godly lifestyle for other youths and young adults to emulate. PSFites has been involved in several CSR activities across the nation. For over 3 years now, this has been an annual commitment. Vision Statement To raise and build a generation of children of Levites whose goal is to: Make Heaven Take as many people along with us. Help youths and parents fulfill destiny and ministry and become a dominant positive influence in RCCG and the world at large Be a model for youths in RCCG and all over the world to follow. Bridge the gap between the younger and older generation particularly between the youths/pastors seeds and the pastors thus stopping the max exodus of youths from the RCCG. Mission Holiness will be our lifestyle We will organize impacting and life changing events and programmes in RCCG parishes, areas, zones, provinces and regions across the world. Our programmes shall be interactive, captivating, motivating,inspiring, educative, informative, and interesting and life changing and shall cover but not be limited to the following core areas: Holiness &amp;amp;, Career, Relationship, Etiquette, Fashion &amp;amp; Dress Sense, Annointing &amp;amp; Deliverance Bible &amp;amp; Church Doctrine, Entrepreneurship &amp;amp; Financial Empowerment, Nation Building, Academics Leadership Spiritual Training and Warfare Health and Psychological Wellbeing Sexual Purity, Spiritual Growth We shall encourage our members to enroll in the Believer’s Baptismal Class, Workers – in – Training and RCCG doctrinal teachings. We shall liaise and partner with the Christ the Redeemer’s Ministries through her daughter organizations such as the Christ the Redeemer’s School Movement, School of Disciples, Redeemed Christian Fellowships, Redeemed Christian Corpers’ Fellowships, etc We shall liaise with the Education and Training arm of the RCCG through the CPLMT –Christian, RCBC - Redeemed Christian Bible College, RECSOM – Redeemed College and School of Missions. We shall liaise with pastors – in – charge of parishes, areas, zones, provinces, regions, countries to ensure our programs have widespread coverage. We shall engage professionals, seasoned and anointed teachers and preachers of the Word and performance coaches to impact, counsel, motivate and challenge members. Networking will be one of the main feature of our activities.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Who are we?</title><link href="https://psfedo3.github.io/who-we-are.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Who are we?" /><published>2020-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://psfedo3.github.io/who-we-are</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://psfedo3.github.io/who-we-are.html">&lt;p&gt;we are blah bala testing testing&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">we are blah bala testing testing</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You’re up and running!</title><link href="https://psfedo3.github.io/articles/Hello-World.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You're up and running!" /><published>2014-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://psfedo3.github.io/articles/Hello-World</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://psfedo3.github.io/articles/Hello-World.html">&lt;p&gt;Next you can update your site name, avatar and other options using the _config.yml file in the root of your repository (shown below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/config.png&quot; alt=&quot;_config.yml&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;supposed to be a comment here&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Spruce</name></author><category term="welcome" /><category term="intro" /><summary type="html">Next you can update your site name, avatar and other options using the _config.yml file in the root of your repository (shown below).</summary></entry></feed>